{
  "sourceFile": "2019-2020-International-Geography-Bee-Regional-Quiz-Tournament-Round-4-Finals.txt",
  "count": 10,
  "items": [
    {
      "qno": 1,
      "question": "This country’s main islands are separated by the bay High Water, while its smaller islands are separated by the Koro Sea. This country is served by the Nadi International Airport. This country’s Mount Tomanivi is the headwaters of its widest river, the Rewa River. The islands of Viti Levu and Vanua Lau are located in, for ten points, what South Pacific Oceanic country with capital Suva?",
      "answer": "Fiji"
    },
    {
      "qno": 2,
      "question": "This country’s highest peak of Tukosmera and Sulphur Bay are the center of the John Frum cargo cult. The Bislama creole is from this country. Pedro Fernandez de Queiros was the first European to land in this country, which was formerly known as the New Hebrides. Tanna and Espiritu Santo are islands in, for ten points, what Melenasian country between Fiji and the Solomon Islands governed from Port Vila.",
      "answer": "Vanuatu"
    },
    {
      "qno": 3,
      "question": "In 2018, one of these locations in London auctioned 1,200 rolls of toilet paper. Secretary of State Mike Pompeo has forbidden flying LGBT pride flags at these locations, an order that some of these locations in Seoul and Chennai have defied. One of these locations was recently moved from Tel Aviv to Jerusalem. For ten points, name these locations where the United States is represented in foriegn countries.",
      "answer": "U.S. embassies"
    },
    {
      "qno": 4,
      "question": "This country is home to the headwaters of the White Drin river and its highest point is Velika Rudoka. This country’s Rugova Canyon is located in its southwest region of Metohija. This country carried out an ethnic cleansing campaign against Serbs in the 1990s. Pristina is the capital of, for ten points, what Albanian majority country that declared independence from Serbia in 2008?",
      "answer": "Kosovo"
    },
    {
      "qno": 5,
      "question": "This city’s Lekki neighborhood is home to the Nike Art Center. This city’s Ikoyi neighborhood is home to an artificial island called Banana Island, which was originally titled Lagoon City. This city is the center of the Nollywood film industry. This city is the largest city in Africa and was replaced by Abuja as its country’s capital. For ten points, name this largest city in Nigeria.",
      "answer": "Lagos"
    },
    {
      "qno": 6,
      "question": "This mountain range is home to Shenandoah National Park, which is contained in the subrange the Blue Ridge Mountains. This mountain range includes the subrange of the Black Mountains, which contain Mount Mitchell. This mountain range’s namesake trail terminates at Mt. Katahdin in Maine. For ten points, name this mountain range in the eastern United States, whose namesake trail starts in Georgia.",
      "answer": "Appalachian Mountains"
    },
    {
      "qno": 7,
      "question": "This desert is home to the Oyu Tolgoi Project, which is operated by the Canadian company, Turquoise Hill Resources. The Dzungarian Basin and Tian Shan Mountains lie to the west of this desert. This desert is home to a supposed “death worm.” This desert is home to the Nemegt Basin, where the first dinosaur eggs were discovered For ten points, name this desert that covers northwest China and Mongolia.",
      "answer": "Gobi Desert"
    },
    {
      "qno": 8,
      "question": "This archipelago is home to a fjord named San Carlos Water, which was an important landing spot for the British during one war. This archipelago is home to Brenton Loch, which is part of the Grantham Sound. Port Louis is the former capital of this archipelago, whose modern day capital is Stanley. For ten points, name this archipelago, which was the subject of a 1980s war between the U.K. and Argentina.",
      "answer": "Falkland Islands"
    },
    {
      "qno": 9,
      "question": "Just off the shore of this peninsula is the Chicxulub Crater, which may have been formed by the impact that wiped out the dinosaurs. That impact also formed the many cenotes sinkholes on this peninsula. The province of Campeche is located on this peninsula, as is the city of Cancun. For ten points, name this Mexican peninsula, which separates the Caribbean Sea from the Gulf of Mexico.",
      "answer": "Yucatan"
    },
    {
      "qno": 10,
      "question": "This country’s national library is housed in the Casa Bauró. This country is home to the the ski resort town of Arinsal. This country’s two princes are comprised of the Bishop of Urgell and the President of France. Along with Spain, this is the only country where Catalan is an official language. The Pyrenees is home to, for ten points, what small country between France and Spain?",
      "answer": "Andorra"
    }
  ]
}